Guide to the Eleanor Foa Dienstag papers, 1955-2011 RL.11862
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Eleanor Foa Dienstag papers
1955-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dienstag, Eleanor Foa
RL.11862
14 Linear Feet
Eleanor Foa Dienstag is a feminist activist, writer, and corporate communications specialist. These materials document her professional life and include drafts of her writings, research on Renée Richards, media appearances, and materials related to the production of her books Whither Thou Goest and In Good Company.
Biographical / Historical
Eleanor Foa Dienstag is a feminist activist, journalist, writer, and photgrapher. She is past president of the American Society of Authors and Journalists, and has been awarded literary residencies at Yaddo and The Virginia Center for the Creative Arts. She is the author of the feminist memoir Whither Thou Goest: the story of an uprooted wife (1976), and In Good Company: a history of the H.J. Heinz Company (1994).
Access Restrictions
Collection contains fragile audio formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Provenance
The Eleanor Foa Dienstag papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2014-2015.
Collection Overview
Collection contains professional papers of Eleanor Foa Dienstag, feminist activist, author, journalist and corporate writer. Materials include Dienstag's writings and appearances in print media, a run of the Outsider's Newsletter, files related to books, Whither Thou Goest and In Good Company: 125 years at the Heinz table, 1869-1994, as well as files related to unfinished biography of transgender activist and tennis champion Renée Richards.
Women authors, American; Feminists -- United States; Dienstag, Eleanor Foa; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Richards, Renée
- In Good Company Book, 1994 (Box 1)
- Articles, 1962-1991 (Box 1)
- FOCUS, Spring 1959 (Box 1)
- Travel Articles, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
- Animal Ranch, 1966 (Box 1)
- The Outsider's Newsletter, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Monocle, v. 5-6, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
- Louis V. Gerstner Speech, Apr. 10th, 1984 (Box 1)
- Mayor Koch Speech (Box 1)
- Living Alone, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
- New York Woman Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
- Cedars-Siani: Discoveries, Winter 2007-Summer 2008 (Box 2)
- Cedars-Siani: Catalyst, Spring/Summer 2008 (Box 2)
- The New Republic, Jan.-Dec. 1965 (Box 2)
- Harper's Magazine, May, 1962 (Box 2)
- Upstate New York (Box 2)
- New York Times Book Review, Feb./Dec. 1983 (Box 2)
- Veteran Feminists of America, 1994-2004 (Box 2)
- Homex Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
- Wither Thou Goest Publicity, 1976 (Box 2)
- Wither Thou Goest Book Proposal (Box 2)
- IFA Correspondence, 1973-1983 (Box 2)
- E.P. Dutton, ICM Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
- Letters From Calvin Trillin, Nora Ephron, et. al., 1974-1977 (Box 2)
- Wither Thou Goest Reviews, 1976-1985 (Box 2)
- New York Times Travel Articles, Dec. 1984 (Box 2)
- Renee Richards Book Research, 1966-1974 (Box 2)
- Renee Richards Correspondence (Box 2)
- Renee Richards Notes (Box 2)
- Renee Richards Anecdotes (Box 2)
- Renee Richards Photos, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
- Renee Richards Interview Tapes Transcript (Box 3)
- Renee Richards Interviews Original Tapes (Box 3)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Contains fragile audio formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
- Renee Richards Manuscript, Chapters 1-13, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
- Newspaper Articles, 1972-1975 (Box 4)
- Ms. Magazine Article, November, 1972 (Box 4)
- Wither Thou Goest Manuscript, 1976 (Box 4)
- Newspaper Clippings and Notes, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
- Fiction, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
- Articles, Clips, Strong Ideas, 1990 (Box 5)
- House of Betrayal: McKee's Notes, 1988-1991 (Box 5)
- Going, Going, Gone Drafts and Notes, 1987-1989 (Box 5)
- Going, Going, Gone Manuscript, 1988 (Box 5)
- Medium Fidelity Manuscript, 1990 (Box 5)
- The CEO and Me, 1984-1988 (Box 5)
- Food Articles, 1998-1999 (Box 6)
- After the Crash, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
- Empty Nest, 1997 (Box 6)
- Websites, 1998-2001 (Box 6)
- General Ideas, 1997-2001 (Box 6)
- Article Ideas, 1999 (Box 6)
- Clayton, Dubilier, and Rice Draft, Chapters 1-8, November 26, 2002 (Box 7)
- General Ideas - Food, 1994-1999 (Box 7)
- Veteran Feminists of America Certificate, November 13, 2006 (Box 7)
- Heinz Project: In Good Company, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
- The New Yorker, Feb 7, 1959 (Box 8)
- Medium Fidelity, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Box 9)
- Weighty Matters/Cutting the Fat, September 3, 1975 (Box 8)
- Upside-Down Princess, 2001 (Box 9)
- Article Ideas (Box 9)
- David Mann Correspondence, 1956-1976 (Box 9)
- Notes/Tie/Silk, 1985-1988 (Box 9)
- Securities Analyst, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
- Movies, 1959-1991 (Box 9)
- History/New York, 1962-1990 (Box 9)
- Oh Joy, Again, 1979-1990 (Box 10)
- Yaddo, 1981 (Box 10)
- Letters from New Choices Readers, 1997 (Box 11)
- Family Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 11)
- Lois and Buck Fields Correspondence, 1995-2015 (Box 11, Box 13)
- Typed Diary Entries, December 29, 1960-January 1, 1962 (Box 12)
- Personal Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 12)
- Sophia, 1999 (Box 12)
- Diary Entries, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
- Fred Croton Correspondence, 1955-1986 (Box 12)
- Book Proposal: Living Alone at Midlife (Box 13)
- Personal Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 13)
- Zena Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 13)
- Donald Justice Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 13)
- The Sunset Maker (Poems/Stories/A Memoir), 1987 (Box 14)
- Selected Poems, 1979 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, 1970-1995 (Box 14-16)
- Poster and Menus (Box 17)
- Life Magazine, 1960-1966 (Box 17)
- Video Tapes and Cassettes, 1994-2000 (Box 17-18)